<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.9.8" xml:lang="en-US">
  <compounddef id="md__2home_2friedel_2devel_2ILLIXR_2plugins_2timewarp__gl_2README" kind="page">
    <compoundname>md__2home_2friedel_2devel_2ILLIXR_2plugins_2timewarp__gl_2README</compoundname>
    <title>timewarp_gl</title>
    <briefdescription>
    </briefdescription>
    <detaileddescription>
<para><anchor id="md__2home_2friedel_2devel_2ILLIXR_2plugins_2timewarp__gl_2README_1autotoc_md43"/> </para>
<sect1 id="md__2home_2friedel_2devel_2ILLIXR_2plugins_2timewarp__gl_2README_1autotoc_md44">
<title>Summary</title>
<para><computeroutput>timewarp_gl</computeroutput> is an OpenGL-based asynchronous rotational reprojection plugin intended for use in the <ref refid="namespaceILLIXR" kindref="compound">ILLIXR</ref> architecture. This plugin implements a rotational reprojection algorithm (i.e. does not reproject position, only rotation).</para>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="md__2home_2friedel_2devel_2ILLIXR_2plugins_2timewarp__gl_2README_1autotoc_md45">
<title>Switchboard connection</title>
<para><computeroutput>timewarp_gl</computeroutput> subscribes to and publishes to several Switchboard plugs and Phonebook resources.</para>
<para><itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>The plugin grabs the GL context from Phonebook. This is necessary to share the eyebuffers with the rendering application (or <ulink url="../illixr_plugins.md#gldemo"><computeroutput>gldemo</computeroutput></ulink>). As this is an OpenGL-based reprojection plugin, it relies on <ulink url="../glossary.md#opengl"><emphasis>OpenGL</emphasis></ulink> resources for the eyebuffers.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><computeroutput>timewarp_gl</computeroutput> subscribes to the most recent pose published by the system. Currently, as our pose-prediction system is still under development, this is not technically accurate; the final, intended functionality is that the timewarp plugin will sample a pose prediction algorithm through an RPC-like mechanism. As we complete our work on our pose prediction system, this plugin will be modified to use this mechanism.</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><computeroutput>timewarp_gl</computeroutput> also subscribes to the most recent frame published by the system. This frame data also includes the pose that was used to render the frame; this is how the timewarp algorithm calculates the &quot;diff&quot; to be used to reproject the frame.</para>
</listitem></itemizedlist>
</para>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="md__2home_2friedel_2devel_2ILLIXR_2plugins_2timewarp__gl_2README_1autotoc_md46">
<title>Environment Variables</title>
<para><bold>TIMEWARP_GL_LOG_LEVEL</bold>: logging level for this plugin, values can be &quot;trace&quot;, &quot;debug&quot;, &quot;info&quot;, &quot;warning&quot;, &quot;error&quot;, &quot;
critical&quot;, or &quot;off&quot;</para>
<para><bold>ILLIXR_TIMEWARP_DISABLE</bold>: whether to disable warping, values can be &quot;True&quot; or &quot;False&quot; (default)</para>
<para><bold>ILLIXR_OFFLOAD_ENABLE</bold>: whether to enable offloading, values can be &quot;True&quot; or &quot;False&quot; (default)</para>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="md__2home_2friedel_2devel_2ILLIXR_2plugins_2timewarp__gl_2README_1autotoc_md47">
<title>Notes</title>
<para>The rotational reprojection algorithm implemented in this plugin is a re-implementation of the algorithm used by the late Jan Paul van Waveren. His invaluable, priceless work in the area of AR/VR has made our project possible. View his codebase <ulink url="https://github.com/KhronosGroup/Vulkan-Samples-Deprecated/tree/master/samples/apps/atw">here</ulink>.</para>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="md__2home_2friedel_2devel_2ILLIXR_2plugins_2timewarp__gl_2README_1autotoc_md48">
<title>Known Issues</title>
<para>As noted above, this plugin currently samples <computeroutput>slow_pose</computeroutput>. This will be changed to sample a <computeroutput>fast_pose</computeroutput> topic through an RPC mechanism. In addition, JMP Van Waveren&apos;s algorithm includes a method for warping between two reprojection matrices based on the actual progress of the display controller&apos;s &quot;scanline&quot;; this is simply commented out in our code, but can be re-enabled when our pose prediction system comes online.</para>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="md__2home_2friedel_2devel_2ILLIXR_2plugins_2timewarp__gl_2README_1autotoc_md49">
<title>Contributions</title>
<para>Contributions are welcome; please raise an issue first, though, as many issues are known and may be a part of our existing internal backlog. </para>
</sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
    <location file="/home/friedel/devel/ILLIXR/plugins/timewarp_gl/README.md"/>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
